Guide to the Samuel Barrington Letterbooks
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Letterbook Two, Series II
  - CORRESPONDENCE FROM ISLAND GOVERNORS
    - Letter from Edward Otto Bayer concerning Antigua's Privy Council., 1778 Sep 16
    - Cover letter from Thomas Jarvis., 1778 Dec 14 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Letter from William Burt containing intelligence of movements of d' Estaing., 1778 Dec 10
    - Letter from Bayer., 1779 Jan 26
    - Letter from Alexander Willock concerning shipping in the West Indies., 1779
    - Letter from Burt regarding his return to Antigua., 1778 Jul 24 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Letter from Burt regarding a request for a sugar convoy to England., 1778 Aug 2
    - Letter of welcome from Burt requesting passage to Antigua as soon as possible., 1778 Aug 3
    - Letter from Burt regarding movements of Marquis de Bouillé., 1778 Sep 14
    - Letter from "the President" [Edward Otto Bayer]: unsigned., 1778 Sep 24 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Letter from Burt regarding a convoy., 1778 Sep 9
    - Letter from Burt regarding the attack of September 7 on Dominica by the French., 1778 Sep 9
    - Intelligence report by Jacob Reter Barents. Detailed account of French attack on Dominica of September 7: copy, 1778 Sep 9
    - Letter from Burt regarding wrong information given about the size of the Toulon Squadron., 1778 Sep 20 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Letter from Burt regarding Dominica and French plans to attack Martinique., 1778 Sep 22
    - Cover letter of relayed correspondence from Burt and de Bouillé signed by William Cumming., 1778 Nov 8 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Letter from Burt regarding d'Arbaud's pending attack on Anguilla., 1778 Oct 13
    - Letter from Edward Otto Bayer regarding the French attack., 1778 Oct 22
    - Letter from John Park regarding a possible prisoner excange., 1778 Oct 22
    - Letter from Burt regarding a damaged schooner which failed to receive aid from two of d'Estaing's ships., 1778 Dec 5 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Letter from Burt congratulating Barrington on a victory over d'Estaing and urging an embargo on merchant shipping to or near the French islands., 1779 Jan 8 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Letter from Burt regarding the retreat of d'Estaing to Fort Royal and regarding provisions., 1779 Jan 21 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Letter from Burt regarding French prisoners and provisions and Barrington's want of men., 1779 Jan 22 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Letter from Valentine Morris asking for gunpowder, and mentioning a copy of a letter from the French King to the Marquis de Bouillé., 1778 Aug 25
    - Letter from Burt regarding the French fleet and French provisions., 1779 Feb 1 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Letter from Burt regarding Gen. Grant and a visit to Barrington., 1779 Feb 3 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Letter from Burt regarding provisions bound for the French islands., 1779 Jan 26
    - Letter from Burt regarding Byron and d'Estaing., 1779 Apr 29 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Letter from de Bouillé regarding Byron and his arrival at Fort Royal: copy, 1779 Apr 22
    - Letter from Michael White regarding intended invasion of St. Vincent., 1778 Sep 18
    - Letter from James Dawson asking Barrington for active defense of the Virgin Islands., 1778 Aug 14 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Letter from Edward Hay regarding prisoners., 1778 Sep 21 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Letter from Hay including account of a riotous attack upon French prisoners by whites and blacks in Bridgetown., 1778 Oct 2
    - Letter from Hay regarding the Marquis de Bouillé's reaction to the attack on the French prisoners., 1778 Nov 4 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Letter from Hay regarding impressment of "straggling sailors.", 1778 Nov 25 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Letter from Hay regarding the arrival of Admiral Byron., 1779 Jan 24
    - Letter from Hay regarding provisions, dispatches and prisoner exchange., 1779 Jan 11 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Letter from Hay regarding unsent dispatches., 1779 Feb 11 (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Letter from Hay regarding dispatches., 1779 Feb 19
    - Letter from William Stuart regarding the French declaration of war with an excerpt from a letter from the Marquis de Bouillé to Stuart of 19 August 1778: copies, 1778 Aug 20 (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Letter from Stuart regarding dispatches and the division of d'Estaing's fleet., 1778 Sep 2 (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - Letter from Stuart regarding the attack by the Toulon Fleet., 1778 Sep 7
    - Letter from Stuart regarding the state of Dominica: copy., 1778 Sep 22
    - Letter from Stuart regarding exchange of prisoners., 1778 Sep 30 (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - Letter from the French King Louis XVI to the Marquis de Bouillé regarding war with England: copy., 1778 Jun 28
  - CORRESPONDENCE FROM VALENTINE MORRIS OF ST. VINCENT'S
    - Letter from Valentine Morris regarding the fall of Dominica and the defense of St. Vincent., 1778 Sep 14 (Box 2, Folder 101)
    - Letter from Frederick Gottsched regarding the fall of Dominica: copy., 1778 Sep 13
    - Sworn statement by Laurent Gillereau regarding the fall of Dominica: copy., 1778 Sep 14
    - Letter from Valentine Morris regarding the taking of Dominica and defense of St. Vincent., 1778 Sep 23 (Box 2, Folder 102)
    - Letter from Morris regarding defense of St. Vincent., 1778 Oct 21
    - Letter from Morris regarding wood for ship repair., 1778 Nov 30 (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - Letter from Morris regarding the French and provisions., 1778 Dec 1 (Box 2, Folder 104)
    - Letter from Morris regarding defense of St. Vincent., 1778 Dec 13
    - Letter from Morris regarding d'Estaing and defense of St. Vincent., 1778 Dec 17 (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - Letter from Morris regarding arrival of Admiral Byron., 1778 Dec 24 (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - Letter from Morris regarding provisions., 1778 Dec 31
    - Letter from Morris regarding St. Lucia., 1779 Jan 3
    - Letter from Morris regarding a prisoner., 1779 Feb 17 (Box 2, Folder 107)
    - Letter from Peter Campbell regarding defense of Tobago., 1778 Sep 11 (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - CORRESPONDENCE FROM LORD GEORGE MACARTNEY
    - Letter from George Macartney regarding the Dutch seizure of an American schooner., 1778 Jul 5 (Box 2, Folder 109)
    - Letter from Macartney regarding Barrington's visit., 1778 Aug 7
    - Letter from Macartney regarding plundering on Dominique: copy., 1778 Sep 2
    - Letter from Macartney requesting assistance., 1778 Sep 13 (Box 2, Folder 110)
    - Letter from Macartney requesting assistance., 1778 Oct 8
    - Extract of a letter from the Earl of Sandwich to Macartney concerning the "Rebel pirates" and the lack of vessels for the West Indies, 1777 Oct 20
    - Letter from Macartney referring to Marquis de Bouillé's intention to invade Grenada: copy., 1778 Oct 11 (Box 2, Folder 111)
    - Letter from Macartney mentioning reinforcements by Germain., 1778 Oct 23
    - Letter from Macartney involving prisoner exchanges with the Marquis de Bouillé., 1778 Nov 8 (Box 2, Folder 112)
    - Letter from Macartney regarding d'Estaing's fleet., 1778 Nov 13 (Box 2, Folder 113)
    - Letter from Macartney regarding exchange of the prisoner Mr. Groves., 1778 Nov 16
    - Letter from Macartney regarding prisoners., 1778 Nov 26
    - Address from the Council and Assembly of Grenada by Speaker Maxwell: copy., 1778 Nov 21
    - Letter from Macartney regarding Lts. Ross and Jones., 1778 Nov 27 (Box 2, Folder 114)
    - Letter from Macartney regarding Capt. Morse., 1778 Dec 3
    - Letter from Macartney regarding defense of Grenada., 1778 Dec 19
    - Letter from Macartney mentioning fugitives from Grenada living at St. Lucia: copy., 1778 Dec 20
    - Note from Macartney., 1778 Dec 20 (Box 2, Folder 115)
    - Letter regarding Capt. Merry from Macartney., 1778 Dec 29
    - Letter from Macartney regarding provisions., 1779 Jan 2 (Box 2, Folder 116)
    - Letter from John Robinson: copy., 1778 Aug 21
    - Letter from Robinson: copy., 1778 Aug 28
    - Letter from Robinson regarding provisions: copy., 1778 Oct 7
    - Letter from Robinson regarding provisions: copy., 1778 Oct 8
    - Letter from Robinson regarding provisions: copy., 1778 Oct 8
    - List titled "Return of Rations drawn at Grenada.", 1779 Jan 4
    - List titled "Return of Expenditures of Provisions at Tobago.", 1779 Jan 4
    - Letter from Macartney regarding the interuption of communications by privateers., 1779 Jan 3 (Box 2, Folder 117)
    - Letter from Macartney regarding d'Estaing and St. Lucia., 1779 Jan 9
    - Letter from Macartney regarding an American privateer invading Tobago., 1779 Jan 20 (Box 2, Folder 118)
    - Letter from Lt. Oswald Clark: copy., 1779 Jan 18
    - Letter from Macartney regarding a plundering privateer., 1779 Jan 21 (Box 2, Folder 119)
    - Letter from Macartney regarding Byron and naval assistance., 1779 Jan 30
    - Letter from Macartney requesting deposition of Thomas Symmers., 1779 Feb 16
    - Letter from B. Douglas regarding the keeling of the Snake., 1778 Nov 7 (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Letter from Capt. John Linzee announcing his arrival in the Pearl from Rhode Island., 1778 Dec 12 (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - Letter from Linzee regarding d'Estaing., 1778 Dec 13
    - Letter from Linzee regarding French fleet sailing from Boston 3 November 1778: copy., 1778 Dec 14
    - Letter from William Nichols on the French fleet., 1778 Dec 7
    - Letter from Linzee regarding ship movements., 1779 Jan 3
    - Letter from Capt. Dacres regarding loss of his command., 1778 Dec 29 (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - Letter from Dacres regarding the loss of the sloop Ceres., 1778 Dec 31
    - Letter from Robert Fanshawe detailing condition of the Carysfort., 1778 Dec 11 (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - Letter from Capt. A. Gardner of the Maidstone announcing his arrival at Antigua and mentioning capture of a French vessel and 1300 hogsheads of Virginia tobacco: copy., 1788 Dec 22 (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - Account of defects of the Maidstone., 1778 Dec 22
    - Account of standing rigging., 1778 Nov 3
    - Letter form Capt. William Lockhart announcing his arrival with supplies., 1779 Feb 5 (Box 3, Folder 125)
  - CORRESPONDENCE FROM THE NAVY BOARD
    - Letter from Navy Board regarding supplies., 1778 Feb 9 (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - Letter from Navy Board regarding supplies., 1778 Apr 20
    - Letter from Navy Board regarding supplies., 1778 Apr 29
    - Letter from Navy Board regarding supplies., 1778 Sep 11
    - Letter from Navy Board regarding supplies., 1779 Feb 19 (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Letter from Navy Board regarding supplies., 1779 Mar 10
    - Letter from Navy Board regarding supplies., 1779 Mar 23
    - Letter from Anderson, master shipwright at Antigua, regarding supply situation at English Harbor., 1778 Apr 12 (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - List by Anderson of men at the shipyard in Antigua., 1778 Aug 12 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - List by Anderson of masts, etc., in the shipyard at Antigua., 1778 Aug 12
  - CORRESPONDENCE FROM THE VICTUALING OFFICE
    - Letter from the Victualing Office., 1778 Feb 9 (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - Letter from the Victualing Office regarding provisions., 1778 Apr 27
    - Letter from the Victualing Office regarding provisions., 1778 Jun 24
    - Account of provisions from the Victualing Office., 1778 Jun 24 (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Letter from Blackburn with a list of ships' provisions: copy., 1778 Apr 21
    - Letter from the Victualing Office regarding provisions., 1778 Jun 24 (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - List of provisions., 1778 Jun 25
    - Letter from the Victualing Office regarding provisions., 1778 Jun 29
    - Letter from the Victualing Office regarding provisions., 1778 Oct 30 (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - List of provisions., 1778 Sep 30
    - Letter from the Victualing Office regarding provisions (Blackburn)., 1778 Oct 28
    - Letter from the Victualing Office regarding provisions., 1778 Oct 30 (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - Victualing contract by John Blackburn with addenda., 1778 Jul 13 (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - Addendum to contract., 1778 Sep 30
    - Letter from the Victualing Office regarding provisions., 1779 Mar 10 (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Letter from Blackburn with provisions account: copy., 1779 Mar 8
  - CORRESPONDENCE FROM THE OFFICE OF SICK AND HURT SEAMEN
    - Letter from Office of Sick and Hurt Seamen regarding medicines., 1778 Mar 2 (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - Directions for administering medicines., 1778 Mar 2
    - Letter regarding the building of a hospital at Antigua: copy., 1778 Mar 2 (Box 3, Folder 138)
    - Letter regarding Antigua and Barbados., 1778 Dec 18
    - Letter regarding sick prisoners., 1779 Mar 12 (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - Contract between Vice Admiral William Parry and William Whitehead regarding the sick., 1773 Jul 20 (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - A "scheme of victualing for prisoners in health.", n.d.
    - Letter from John Crawford, surgeon at Barbados., 1779 Feb 13 (Box 3, Folder 141)
    - Letter from Crawford., 1779 Mar 22
    - Letter from Anthony Gregg regarding medical contracts., 1779 Mar 6 (Box 3, Folder 142)
    - Letter regarding the hospital at Barbados., 1774 Oct 4
    - Abstract of a letter from the Commissioners of Sick and Hurt Seamen., 1775 Jul 21
    - Letter from Crawford regarding medical treatment of seamen., 1779 May 15 (Box 3, Folder 143)
    - Letter from Whitehall Treasury Chambers regarding victualing ships., 1778 Jun 8 (Box 3, Folder 144)
    - Letter from Whitehall regarding victualing ships., 1778 Jul 27
    - Letters from John Robinson of the Treasury Office: two copies., 1778 Jun 8
    - Letter from John Robinson regarding provisions., 1778 Oct 8 (Box 3, Folder 145)
- Oversize, 1779 Jul 2
  - Printed broadsheet with manuscript notes by Byron regarding ship signals., 1779 Jul 2 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 146)
  - Letter from Valentine Morris asking for gunpowder, and mentioning a copy of a letter from the French King to the Marquis de Bouillé., 1778 Aug 25 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 147)
  - Letter from Michael White regarding intended invasion of St. Vincent., 1778 Sep 18 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 148)
  - Letter from Stuart regarding the state of Dominica: copy., 1778 Sep 22 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 149)
  - Letter from Louis XIV: copy, 1778 Jun 28 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 150)
  - Letter from Morris regarding defense of St. Vincent., 1778 Oct 21 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 151)